<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-10T10:46:59+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Apache Software Foundation - Logging Services</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Hunt bugs for Log4j (and get paid for it)</title><link href="/blog/2024/08/12/log4j-bug-bounty.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hunt bugs for Log4j (and get paid for it)" /><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2024/08/12/log4j-bug-bounty</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2024/08/12/log4j-bug-bounty.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="apache-log4j-participates-in-the-bug-bounty-program">Apache Log4j participates in the bug bounty program</h1>

<p>We were proud to be <a href="/blog/2023/12/14/announcing-support-from-the-stf.html">supported by the STF</a> last year.
This support helped us to fix many bugs, rewrite documentation, and improve the overall quality of the codebase and security.</p>

<p>Building on this support, we are excited to announce our participation in the <a href="https://yeswehack.com/programs/log4j-bug-bounty-program">YesWeHack</a> bug bounty program.
This initiative allows you to hunt bugs in Log4j and get paid for your contributions.</p>

<p>Our participation in this program wouldn’t have been possible without the 
generous support of our friends at the STF, who provided the necessary funds to 
reward your efforts. The STF not only supports us but also assists many other projects. 
You can learn more about their mission by reading their
<a href="https://www.sovereigntechfund.de/news/calling-all-security-researchers">official announcement on their website</a>.</p>

<p>We want to thank the STF and YesWeHack for their support.</p>

<p>We encourage all security researchers and developers to join us in this effort. 
Your contributions can help make Log4j more secure and reliable and reward your efforts.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Apache Log4j" /><category term="Bug Bounty" /><category term="Open Source" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some Apache Logging Services projects, such as Log4j, are participating in the YesWeHack bug bounty program.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcoming Jan Friedrich to the Apache Logging Services PMC</title><link href="/blog/2024/08/08/welcome-to-the-pmc-jan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcoming Jan Friedrich to the Apache Logging Services PMC" /><published>2024-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2024/08/08/welcome-to-the-pmc-jan</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2024/08/08/welcome-to-the-pmc-jan.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="welcoming-jan-friedrich-to-the-apache-logging-services-pmc">Welcoming Jan Friedrich to the Apache Logging Services PMC</h1>

<p>We are happy to announce that Jan Friedrich has been invited to join the Apache Logging Services PMC. Jan joined the project only this year. His contributions to Log4net have been substantial and have significantly improved the project.</p>

<p>Instead of introducing him ourselves, we asked Jan to share a little of himself:</p>

<p>“I’m Jan Friedrich (FreeAndNil), hailing from Germany, and I’ve been a developer for 25 years. Over the past two decades, I’ve specialized in Delphi &amp; C# and have nearly 20 years of experience using log4net. For the past two years, I’ve also been actively contributing to the development of log4net. On a personal note, I’m a proud parent of three wonderful kids. I look forward to sharing my expertise and learning from all of you.”</p>

<h2 id="a-community-built-on-collaboration-and-innovation">A Community Built on Collaboration and Innovation</h2>

<p>The Apache Logging Services community is a lively and passionate group dedicated to open-source software and top-notch logging solutions. We thrive on collaboration and innovation.</p>

<h2 id="open-arms-for-newcomers">Open Arms for Newcomers</h2>

<p>We’re always excited to welcome newcomers, whether you’re an experienced 
developer or just starting. Apache Logging Services is a place to contribute, 
learn, and grow. Our community is here to help and collaborate with anyone who shares our passion.</p>

<p>Get in touch through GitHub Issues/Discussions or our mailing lists.</p>

<p>Join us, and let’s build something great together!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Logging Services" /><category term="Apache" /><category term="Community" /><category term="Open Source" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Highlighting the impactful journey of Jan Friedrich with Apache Logging Services since 2020, and his notable contributions to Log4net.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Apache Log4j - Interview at Community Over Code 2024</title><link href="/blog/2024/07/25/Log4j-At-Community-Over-Code-2024.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apache Log4j - Interview at Community Over Code 2024" /><published>2024-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2024/07/25/Log4j-At-Community-Over-Code-2024</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2024/07/25/Log4j-At-Community-Over-Code-2024.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="apache-log4j-at-community-over-code-2024-in-bratislava">Apache Log4j at Community Over Code 2024 in Bratislava</h1>

<p>On July 25, 2024, Apache Log4j was featured at the Community Over Code conference in Bratislava.
Matt Sicker and Piotr Karwasz, two of the project’s key contributors, shared insights into the history and future of Log4j.</p>

<p>If you are interested in what we learned about security and how we want to 
improve Log4j further, please watch the full interview done by Rich Bowen for
the ASF.</p>

<div class="youtube-placeholder yt-container-Hpe7p24DQo0" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <img src="/img/video-placeholders/Hpe7p24DQo0.jpg" alt="Video thumbnail" />
</div>
<div class="youtube-placeholder-description">
  Clicking on this image will load the video and send data from and to YouTube/Google.
</div>
<style>
  .youtube-placeholder {
    width: 560px; 
    height: auto;
  }
  .youtube-placeholder-description {
    color: gray;
    font-style: italic;
  }
</style>

<script>
  document.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded', function() {
    var container = document.querySelector('.yt-container-Hpe7p24DQo0');
    function addElement() {
      var iframe = document.createElement('iframe');
      iframe.setAttribute('width', '560');
      iframe.setAttribute('height', '315');
      iframe.setAttribute('src', 'https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Hpe7p24DQo0?autoplay=1');
      iframe.setAttribute('title', 'YouTube video player');
      iframe.setAttribute('frameborder', '0');
      iframe.setAttribute('allow', 'accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share');
      iframe.setAttribute('allowfullscreen', '');
      container.innerHTML = '';
      container.appendChild(iframe);
    }
    container.addEventListener('click', addElement);
  });
</script>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Apache Log4j" /><category term="Anniversary" /><category term="Open Source" /><category term="Community" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Piotr Karwasz and Matt Sicker discuss the history and future of Apache Log4j at the Community Over Code conference.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating Two Decades of Innovation with Apache Log4j</title><link href="/blog/2023/12/18/20-years-of-innovation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating Two Decades of Innovation with Apache Log4j" /><published>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2023/12/18/20-years-of-innovation</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2023/12/18/20-years-of-innovation.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="two-decades-of-apache-log4j-a-journey-of-resilience-and-innovation">Two Decades of Apache Log4j: A Journey of Resilience and Innovation</h1>

<p>Today, December 17, 2023 marks a significant milestone for the Apache Logging Services project, 
as we celebrate 20 years since the inception of Log4j 1. 
This journey, spanning two decades, has been one of constant evolution, growth, and community spirit.</p>

<h2 id="a-timeline-of-success-and-learning">A Timeline of Success and Learning</h2>

<p>From the early days of Log4j 1, we have witnessed numerous releases, 
welcomed many new committers and PMC members, and seen the launch of various side
projects as Log4xx, Chainsaw or Log4php. The recent addition of 
Apache Flume has further broadened our suite of logging
tools, showcasing our commitment to providing diverse and robust solutions.</p>

<p>We are incredibly proud of the learning curve we experienced with Log4j 1. 
Every mistake was a stepping stone towards the development of Log4j 2, 
which has surpassed all our previous projects in scope and impact.</p>

<h2 id="overcoming-challenges-together">Overcoming Challenges Together</h2>

<p>The Log4shell incident was a critical period for us. However, the strength 
and support of not only our community but also the global open-source community 
were astounding. Together, we transformed a challenge into an opportunity to create
the most secure logging framework to date. The extensive code reviews and 
collaborative efforts post-Log4shell have significantly fortified 
Log4j’s security features.</p>

<h2 id="looking-ahead-with-excitement">Looking Ahead with Excitement</h2>

<p>The future looks bright as we eagerly anticipate the release of Log4j 3. 
Alongside, we are preparing for new versions of Apache Flume, a logging processor, 
and other exciting side projects. These developments are a testament to our 
commitment to innovation and excellence.</p>

<h2 id="a-community-that-values-collaboration">A Community That Values Collaboration</h2>

<p>At the heart of our success is our community spirit, perfectly encapsulated 
in the Apache Software Foundation’s motto, “Community Over Code.” 
This philosophy has been our guiding light, ensuring that we prioritize 
collaboration, mutual respect, and collective growth.</p>

<p>We warmly invite you to join us in this celebratory moment. Whether you 
are a seasoned contributor or new to the open-source world, there is a 
place for you in the Apache Logging Services community. Together, let’s 
continue to innovate, learn, and build a future that echoes the resilience 
and spirit of the past two decades.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Apache Log4j" /><category term="Anniversary" /><category term="Open Source" /><category term="Community" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Marking 20 years of growth and resilience with Apache Log4j, from its inception in 2003 to the upcoming launch of Log4j 3.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Log4j: A New Chapter with STF Funding</title><link href="/blog/2023/12/14/announcing-support-from-the-stf.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Log4j: A New Chapter with STF Funding" /><published>2023-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2023/12/14/announcing-support-from-the-stf</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2023/12/14/announcing-support-from-the-stf.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="receiving-support-from-the-sovereign-tech-fund">Receiving Support from the Sovereign Tech Fund</h1>

<p>For a long time, Apache Log4j has thrived through the dedication and contributions 
of our community, relying mostly on unpaid volunteers. Today, we’re excited to announce 
a pivotal moment in our journey – the Sovereign Tech Fund (STF) has chosen to support us in the further development of specific Log4j projects.</p>

<p>The STF, known for its commitment to critical projects 
(<a href="https://www.sprind.org/de/projekte/sovereign-tech-fund/">Sovereign Tech Fund</a>), 
recognizes the significance of Log4j in the global tech landscape. This support 
is a testament to the essential role Log4j plays in the IT infrastructure.</p>

<h2 id="focused-development-and-security-enhancement">Focused Development and Security Enhancement</h2>

<p>We’re honored that three of our maintainers - <a href="https://grobmeier.solutions">Christian Grobmeier</a>, 
Piotr Karwasz, and <a href="https://volkan.yazi.ci">Volkan Yazıcı</a> - are being supported through 
this initiative. Collaborating closely with the Project Management Committee (PMC), 
their focus will be on enhancing security, elevating code quality, and adding new, 
advanced features.</p>

<p>We have already made significant progress: implemented a CI-based
release pipeline, modernized the code base and dependencies, started
publishing <a href="https://logging.apache.org/logging-parent/latest/#cyclonedx-sbom">Software Bill of Materials (SBOM) and Vulnerability Disclosure Report (VDR)</a>
for released artifacts, and several other enhancements. This funding 
will also enable us to substantially improve our documentation, tests, and overall stability.</p>

<h2 id="broadening-our-horizons">Broadening Our Horizons</h2>

<p>This is an extraordinary opportunity for Log4j and the Logging Services team. It enables us to refine our library, 
making it more user-friendly and maintaining our position as a leading logging solution. 
Our team’s size and expertise allow us to respond swiftly to security issues. 
With the STF’s support, we can further enhance the security and stability that 
enterprises and our diverse user base have come to expect from us.</p>

<p>Without this funding, many of these improvements would not have been feasible. 
It marks a significant leap in our ability to serve the community and 
contribute to the open-source ecosystem.</p>

<h2 id="acknowledgments-and-future-endeavors">Acknowledgments and Future Endeavors</h2>

<p>On a personal note, we would like to extend our gratitude to the (<a href="https://www.inoeg.de/">InÖG</a>) 
for their pivotal role in facilitating these developments. They made us aware of the STF 
during our participation in their remarkable project “<a href="https://www.dialog-cybersicherheit.de/b3/">Buntes Bug Bounty</a>” 
program, a commendable open-source project to bolster software security 
(<a href="https://www.dialog-cybersicherheit.de/workstreams/">Dialog-Cybersicherheit</a>) in Germany.</p>

<p>As we embark on this new chapter, we invite the global tech community to join us 
in celebrating this milestone. Your support and contributions have brought us here, 
and together, we’ll continue to strengthen the foundation of digital infrastructure 
for a safer, more robust technological future.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Apache Log4j" /><category term="Sovereign Tech Fund" /><category term="Open Source" /><category term="Community" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Celebrating a significant milestone in Log4j's journey with support from the Sovereign Tech Fund.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Upgrade to Apache Commons Logging 1.3.0</title><link href="/blog/2023/12/02/apache-common-logging-1.3.0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Upgrade to Apache Commons Logging 1.3.0" /><published>2023-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2023/12/02/apache-common-logging-1.3.0</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2023/12/02/apache-common-logging-1.3.0.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="apache-commons-logging">Apache Commons Logging</h1>

<p><a href="https://commons.apache.org/proper/commons-logging/">Apache Commons Logging</a> (JCL) is one of the oldest Java logging API
available.
Released for the first time in 2002, it immediately saw a widespread adoption in the Java community.</p>

<p>While newer APIs, like SLF4J and our own Log4j API, appeared over time, even in 2023 it is hard to find an application stack
that does not depend on JCL.
According to Sonatype, Apache Commons Logging is used in <a href="https://central.sonatype.com/artifact/commons-logging/commons-logging">over 1 million artifacts</a>,
while the second place is taken by SLF4J with <a href="https://central.sonatype.com/artifact/org.slf4j/slf4j-api">almost 40 thousand artifacts</a>.</p>

<h2 id="version-130">Version 1.3.0</h2>

<p>After more than 9 years since its previous release (version 1.2 released in July 2014), Apache Commons Logging released
a new 1.3.0 version today (cf. <a href="https://lists.apache.org/thread/wx6v7wwhbnk64nx708hszctzv8fdsvdl">announcement</a>).
Among the most prominent changes, the new version:</p>

<ul>
  <li>forwards logging to the Log4j API out-of-the-box (if present),</li>
  <li>also supports forwarding to SLF4J,</li>
  <li>adds support for the Java Platform Module System (JPMS) with the module name <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">org.apache.commons.logging</code>.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="upgrade-instructions-log4j-corelogback">Upgrade instructions (Log4j Core/Logback)</h2>

<p>The upgrade path for users of the Log4j Core and Logback logging backends is easy.
The first step is upgrading <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">commons-logging</code>.
In Maven this can be done using dependency management.</p>

<div class="language-xml highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="nt">&lt;dependencyManagement&gt;</span>
    <span class="nt">&lt;dependencies&gt;</span>
        <span class="nt">&lt;dependency&gt;</span>
            <span class="nt">&lt;groupId&gt;</span>commons-logging<span class="nt">&lt;/groupId&gt;</span>
            <span class="nt">&lt;artifactId&gt;</span>commons-logging<span class="nt">&lt;/artifactId&gt;</span>
            <span class="nt">&lt;version&gt;</span>1.3.0<span class="nt">&lt;/version&gt;</span>
        <span class="nt">&lt;/dependency&gt;</span>
    <span class="nt">&lt;/dependencies&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;/dependencyManagement&gt;</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The second step consists in removing obsolete dependencies.
Since version 1.2 only supported old generation logging backends out-of-the-box (<a href="https://logging.apache.org/log4j/1.x/">Log4j 1.x</a>,
<a href="https://avalon.apache.org">Avalon</a> and <a href="https://javalogging.sourceforge.net">Lumberjack</a>), the Java community developed
many <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">LogFactory</code> implementations and complete Apache Commons Logging replacements:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://mvnrepository.com/artifact/org.slf4j/jcl-over-slf4j"><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">org.slf4j:jcl-over-slf4j</code></a> (replacement),</li>
  <li><a href="https://mvnrepository.com/artifact/org.springframework/spring-jcl"><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">org.springframework:spring-jcl</code></a> (replacement),</li>
  <li>our own <a href="https://mvnrepository.com/artifact/org.apache.logging.log4j/log4j-jcl"><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">org.apache.logging.log4j:log4j-jcl</code></a>
(<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">LogFactory</code> implementation).</li>
</ul>

<p>These artifacts can be <strong>safely</strong> removed from your dependency stack.
For JPMS users this operation is even <strong>required</strong>.</p>

<p>To do so Maven users can use exclusions:</p>

<div class="language-xml highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="nt">&lt;dependency&gt;</span>
    <span class="nt">&lt;groupId&gt;</span>org.springframework<span class="nt">&lt;/groupId&gt;</span>
    <span class="nt">&lt;artifactId&gt;</span>spring-jcl<span class="nt">&lt;/artifactId&gt;</span>
    <span class="nt">&lt;exclusions&gt;</span>
        <span class="nt">&lt;exclusion&gt;</span>
            <span class="nt">&lt;groupId&gt;</span>org.springframework<span class="nt">&lt;/groupId&gt;</span>
            <span class="nt">&lt;artifactId&gt;</span>spring-jcl<span class="nt">&lt;/artifactId&gt;</span>
        <span class="nt">&lt;/exclusion&gt;</span>
    <span class="nt">&lt;/exclusions&gt;</span>
<span class="nt">&lt;/dependency&gt;</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>and to prevent regressions, add those dependencies to a <a href="https://maven.apache.org/enforcer/enforcer-rules/bannedDependencies.html"><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">bannedDependencies</code> Maven Enforcer rule</a>.</p>

<h2 id="upgrade-instructions-log4j-1xreload4j-users">Upgrade instructions (Log4j 1.x/Reload4j users)</h2>

<p>For users that use Log4j 1.x or Reload4j as logging backend the upgrade is more complicated: version 1.3.0 disabled the Log4j 1.x backend by default.</p>

<p>Log4j 1.x/Reload4j users are:</p>

<ul>
  <li>encouraged to migrate to Log4j 2.x Core (cf. <a href="https://logging.apache.org/log4j/2.x/manual/migration.html">migration guide</a>) or Logback,</li>
  <li>if that is not possible (or if a transitional period is required) they need to add a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">commons-logging.properties</code> file to their applications containing:</li>
</ul>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>org.apache.commons.logging.Log = org.apache.commons.logging.impl.Log4JLogger
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="jpms-users">JPMS users</h2>

<p>The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">org.apache.commons.logging</code> JPMS module has an <strong>optional</strong> dependency on the Log4j API.
In order for the JVM to automatically add the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">org.apache.logging.log4j</code> module to your application’s runtime, you need to add:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>requires org.apache.logging.log4j;
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>to your application’s module descriptor.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Apache" /><category term="Commmons Logging" /><category term="Open Source" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Instructions to upgrade application to Apache Commons Logging 1.3.0.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcoming Stephen Webb to the Apache Logging Services PMC</title><link href="/blog/2023/11/28/new-pmc-member.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcoming Stephen Webb to the Apache Logging Services PMC" /><published>2023-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2023/11/28/new-pmc-member</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2023/11/28/new-pmc-member.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="welcoming-stephen-webb-to-the-apache-logging-services-community">Welcoming Stephen Webb to the Apache Logging Services community</h1>

<p>We are thrilled to take this moment to celebrate and acknowledge Stephen Webb, 
who joined the Apache Logging Services community back in 2020. 
Stephen’s journey with us has been nothing short of remarkable, 
especially his substantial contributions to the Log4cxx project.</p>

<p>Stephen’s work has played a vital role in enhancing Log4cxx, showcasing 
his expertise and dedication to improving our logging solutions.</p>

<p>That’s why we invited Stephen to the Apache Logging Services PMC.</p>

<h2 id="a-community-built-on-collaboration-and-innovation">A Community built on collaboration and innovation</h2>

<p>The Apache Logging Services community is a vibrant and dynamic group, 
united by our passion for open-source software and our commitment to 
delivering top-notch logging solutions. We’re proud of the 
collaborative environment we’ve fostered, where ideas thrive and innovation 
is the norm.</p>

<h2 id="open-arms-for-newcomers">Open arms for newcomers</h2>

<p>In the spirit of growth and learning, we also want to extend a warm 
welcome to newcomers. Whether you’re an experienced developer or just starting,
Apache Logging Services is a place where you can contribute, learn, and grow. 
Our community is always glad to help, guide, and collaborate with 
anyone who shares our passion for open-source software and logging solutions.</p>

<p>Please reach out using GitHub Issues/Discussions or our mailing lists.</p>

<p>Join us, if you want to be part of our project. Let’s build together!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Logging Services" /><category term="Apache" /><category term="Community" /><category term="Open Source" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Highlighting the impactful journey of Stephen Webb with Apache Logging Services since 2020, and his notable contributions to Log4cxx.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcoming Apache Flume to Apache Logging Services</title><link href="/blog/2023/11/17/flume-joins-logging-services.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcoming Apache Flume to Apache Logging Services" /><published>2023-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/2023/11/17/flume-joins-logging-services</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2023/11/17/flume-joins-logging-services.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="welcoming-the-apache-flume-team-to-apache-logging-services">Welcoming the Apache Flume Team to Apache Logging Services</h1>

<p>We are excited to announce that <a href="https://flume.apache.org"><strong>Apache Flume</strong></a> is now a part of our Logging Services family. 
Flume is renowned for its distributed, reliable, and available service, specializing 
in efficiently collecting, aggregating, and moving large volumes of log data.</p>

<p>The journey of Flume has been remarkable. Unfortunately, the Flume team had struggles
with growing and remained a small team. Still, they caught the attention
of several Logging Services committers. Impressed by its 
capabilities and potential, both the Flume community and our team saw a 
unique opportunity for collaboration and bringing two small teams together.</p>

<h2 id="a-unified-force-in-logging">A Unified Force in Logging</h2>

<p>This integration is more than just a merger of two services; it’s the coming 
together of like-minded communities aiming for excellence in logging solutions. 
The decision to merge was driven by our shared vision of offering robust, 
scalable, and efficient logging services.</p>

<h2 id="extending-our-portfolio">Extending Our Portfolio</h2>

<p>Flume’s addition significantly extends our own Logging portfolio. Its unique approach 
to handling large-scale log data complements our existing solutions, creating a 
more comprehensive suite of tools for our users.</p>

<h2 id="looking-forward">Looking Forward</h2>

<p>Plans are already underway to push Flume to a new release, one that incorporates 
our combined expertise and the latest in logging technology.</p>

<h2 id="free-and-open-source-apache-license">Free and Open Source, Apache License</h2>

<p>As always, Apache Flume is developed under the Apache License. You can find its 
source code <a href="https://github.com/apache/flume">here</a>. While we are still merging
our efforts, you can already contribute and send pull requests. We value the 
principles of open source and encourage the community to participate in 
Flume’s ongoing development.</p>

<h2 id="join-us">Join Us</h2>

<p>We are also opening our doors wider, welcoming new contributors and other 
interested individuals who wish to be part of this exciting journey. Whether 
you’re an experienced developer or just starting out, there’s a place for you here.</p>

<p>If you’re as excited about this development as we are and want to learn more 
or contribute, we encourage you to reach out. Let’s shape the future of logging services together!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Logging Services" /><category term="Flume" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apache Flume joins the Apache Logging Services project, bringing its powerful data aggregation capabilities to enhance our logging solutions.]]></summary></entry></feed>